## AMITKUMAR ASHOK CHAUHAN

INDIA Mobile: +91 9624201664, +91 7878355225 E-mail: chauhanamit143@yahoo.com



Customer-focused IT Support with 9 years of experience with a broad-spectrum of computer operating systems applications and hardware. Exceptional customer service and communication skills; consistently conveys competence and concern to end users. Strong ability to effectively multitask and to perform with a sense of urgency for rapid issue resolution. Comfortable in working independently as well as a team member Excellent multitasking, problem solving and resource management skills Passionate to acquire new skills and adapt them to deliver results Excellent time-management and communication skills Confident and patient worker with an ability to develop and maintain professional report with colleagues and clients through effective communication.

### Experiences

# 21 SEP 2021- PRESENT <u>HARDWARE & NETWORK ENGINEER</u> GANGA FASHIONS PVT. LTD.

- ▶ Basic Knowledge of SAP HANA, installation and configuration.
- ➤ Hands-on experience for installing and troubleshooting WindowsOS (Win 7, Win 10 & Win 11 Server 2012, 2016 & 2019).
- ➤ Installation and Troubleshoot for Cad Software Like AutoCAD, Free Cad, Solid Work, IronCad, Catia and other Software Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- ➤ Software installation, configuration, and troubleshooting for end users. (CAD software's 2D\3D, MS Office applications, Antivirus).
- ➤ Configuring and troubleshooting of Desktop/Laptops.
- Troubleshoot Follow any problems the customers are having
- Meet all of the appointments in a given day
- ➤ Manage Office 365 application MS Exchange, MS Teams, OneDrive & SharePoint (Creatingusers, license allocation, access configuration).
- Manage Antivirus Server and Application (Installation, Policy Check, Updates).
- Firewall (Basic Knowledge about how Firewall policy works).
- Ensure security of data, network access and backup systems.
- ▶ Inventory management (Keeping inventory of all IT assets).
- ➤ Coordination with Vendor for closing service provider related issues.
- Linux server troubleshooting and installation (Good to have basic knowledge).
- ▶ Hands-on experience for operating remote support tools (TeamViewer, Any desk etc.)
- ➤ Managing backup and recovery local server.
- Troubleshooting Network related queries LAN, WAN and VPN.
- ➤ Working and configuring NAS Device for user. (Synology and WD)
- Having knowledge of Blackbox. (User and data access controlling)

### 19 MAY 2018-31 JUL 2021 <u>DESKTOP SUPPORT SR.ENGG L1, L2</u> LILY PACKERS PVT. LTD.

- Configure antivirus software to fully protect IT environment.
- Installation and Troubleshoot for Cad Software Like AutoCAD, Free Cad, Solid Work, IronCad, Catia and other Software Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Responsible for the maintenance and repair of routers, switches, and backup systems integral tonetwork functionality.
- Monitor the performance of the computer systems and address issues as they arise.
- > Provide technical support for software reconfigurations to aid in function customization.
- > Test software performance throughout the desktop network to ensure peak performance.
- Install computer hardware and software on desktops to keep versions current.
- ➤ Initiate and complete Microsoft Windows server operating system updates. Observationthrough CCTV camera and trouble shooting.
- Network design and managing purchase for IT equipment.

# FEB 2014- FEB 2018 <u>DESKTOP SUPPORT SR. ENGINEER L1, L2</u> NITI DISTRIBUTORS PVT. LTD.

- ➤ Workshop in charge doing all transactions in desktop & laptops.
- ➤ Repairing all assemble and branded desktops, laptops and Printers.
- ▶ Remote support to all other branches in different Countries and Customers.
- Maintaining all staff computers, server, software, printers and networking.
- Mail supporting like an outlook express to all other branches.
- ➤ Observation through CCTV camera and trouble shooting.
- ➤ LA MALSON ROYALE HOTEL 3 star in Kenya as IT Support Engg.

  Maintaining all IT Equipment's (Computer system, Bio-metric system, CCTV, SERVER)

### Education

#### **EDUCATION QUALIFICATION**

- ▶ BCA graduate from (Udhna Academy College of Computer Application & IT) College. Affiliated with VNSGU University in year 2013 with 54 %.
- ➤ Passed higher secondary in year 2010 with 39 %.
- ➤ Passed High school from GSEB board in year 2006 with 61%.
- ➤ Passed I.T.I.(ELECTRONICS) from NCVT in year 2008 with 67 %.
- ▶ Passed TALLY from I.T.I. NCVT in year 2007 with 57%.

#### **Portfolio**

Address - 94, Umiya nagar-2, Navagam Dindoli Road, Udhana, Surat.State: Gujarat.

Pin No.: 394210.

Nationality- Indian
Gender - Male
DOB- 31/10/1989
Marital Status- Married

E-mail – <u>chauhanamit143@yahoo.com</u>
Father's Name - ASHOK ZAGRU CHAUHAN
Mother's Name - KAILASHI ASHOK CHAUHAN

Strength (Skills) - Communication skills, Take ownership, Self Confidence, Honesty, management,

Team Work, creative, hardworking, Fast leaner. Leadership, Integrity.

Hobbies - Movies, Travelling, Drawing, Gaming, Foodies.

Signature Amitkumar Ashok Chauhan

Date: